Believe in the impossible
Meru is a adventure, documentary film directed by Jimmy Chin.
Meru is the electrifying story of three elite American climbers—Conrad Anker,
Jimmy Chin, and Renan Ozturk—bent on achieving the impossible.
Himself, played by Conrad Anker.
Himself, played by Jimmy Chin.
Himself, played by Renan Öztürk.
Himself, played by Jon Krakauer.
Herself, played by Jenni Lowe-Anker.
Herself, played by Amee Hinkley.
Meru is a 2015 documentary film chronicling the 2011 first ascent of a new climbing route up the prow
of the dramatic Shark's Fin on the northeast side of Meru Peak in the Indian Himalayas.
The route required a complex range of alpine climbing, big wall climbing, and aid climbing techniques, and had rebuffed many
famous climbers, including the team of Conrad Anker, Jimmy Chin, and Renan Ozturk who are featured in the film.
It was co-directed by the husband and wife team of Jimmy Chin
and Elizabeth Chai Vasarhelyi, and won the 'U.S.
Audience Documentary Award' at the 2015 Sundance Film Festival.
The film explores themes of himalaya mountain range, based on
true story, climbing, india, mountain climbing.